Finding Aid for President (University of Michigan) records, 1967-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files 1967/68-2008/09
  - 1990-1991
    - Awards
      - Henry Russel (Box 246)
      - Raoul Wallenberg Medal and Lecture (Box 246)
        (various)
      - University (Box 246)
    - Budget
      - Indirect Costs (Box 246)
      - State Appropriations, 3 folders (Box 246)
      - University, 2 folders (Box 246)
    - Business Higher Education
      - Business Higher Education Forum (Box 246)
      - Business Roundtable (Box 246)
    - Business and Industry (Box 246)
    - Campus
      - General (Box 246)
      - Campus Pulse Group (Box 246)
      - Campus Safety, 2 folders (Box 246)
      - Campus Safety Task Force (Box 247)
    - Campus Compact
      - General (Box 247)
      - Michigan (Box 247)
    - Centers (UM)
      - General (Box 247)
      - Center for the Continuing Education of Women (Box 247)
    - Change Group (Box 247)
    - Commencements (Box 247)
    - Committee on Institutional Advancement (Box 247)
    - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) (Box 247)
    - Community Affairs, Vice President for (Box 247)
    - Condolences and Get-well Wishes (Box 247)
    - Congratulations and Commendations (Box 247)
    - Cost of Higher Education Task Force, 2 folders (Box 247)
    - Dearborn Campus, 2 folders (Box 247)
    - Detroit (Box 247)
    - Development, Vice President for
      - General, 3 folders (Box 247)
      - Advisory Group (Box 248)
      - Capital Campaign, 3 folders (Box 248)
      - Corporations (Box 248)
      - Events, 2 folders (Box 248)
      - International Committee for the University (Box 248)
    - Disabled Students (Box 248)
    - Duderstadt, James J.
      - General (Box 248)
      - Meetings and Appointments, 2 folders (Box 248)
      - Notes (Box 248)
      - Speeches, 2 folders (Box 248)
    - Economic Status of the Faculty, Committee on the (CESF) (Box 248)
    - Environment (Box 248)
    - Ethics (Box 248)
    - Executive Officers (Box 248)
    - Fellowships (Box 248)
    - Financial Officer, Vice President and Chief
      - General, 2 folders (Box 248)
      - Investments and Insurance (Box 249)
      - Parking Operations (Box 249)
      - Plant (Box 249)
    - Fleming Building (Box 249)
    - Flint Campus (Box 249)
    - Flint Initiatives (Box 249)
    - Foundations
      - General (Box 249)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 249)
      - Kellogg Foundation (Box 249)
    - Futures Group (Box 249)
    - General Counsel, Office of (Box 249)
    - Government Relations, Vice President for
      - General, 3 folders (Box 249)
      - Residency (Box 249)
    - Government-University-Industry (Box 249)
    - Graduate Student Assistants (Box 249)
    - Grievances
      - Faculty/Staff (Box 268)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2021 ]
      - Students (Box 268)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2066 ]
    - Higher Education
      - General (Box 249)
      - Doctoral Pipeline (Box 249)
      - Science Education (Box 249)
    - Honorary Degrees
      - General (Box 249)
      - Nominations, 2 folders (Box 249)
    - Information Technology, Vice Provost for (Box 249)
    - Institutes (UM) (Box 250)
    - Institutional Advancement Committee (Box 250)
    - International Issues, 3 folders (Box 250)
    - International Exchange Programs
      - General, 2 folders (Box 250)
      - Africa
        - General (Box 250)
        - South African Education Program
          - General (Box 250)
          - Student Evaluation (Box 268)
        - South Africa Mid-Career Fellowships (Box 250)
      - China and Taiwan
        - General, 4 folders (Box 250)
        - Chinese Delegation July 17-19, 1986 (Box 250)
        - Shapiro visit to China May 3-18, 1981 (Box 250)
        - US-PRC Joint Commission on Cooperation in Science and Technology 1985 (Box 250)
      - Egypt (Box 250)
      - England
        - General (Box 250)
        - Oriel College (Box 250)
      - France (Box 250)
      - Fulbright Exchange (Box 250)
      - Germany
        - General (Box 250)
        - Deutscher Akademischer Austausch Dienst (DAAD) (Box 250)
        - University of Saarland (Box 250)
      - India (Box 251)
      - Iran (Box 251)
      - Ireland (Box 251)
      - Israel (Box 251)
      - Italy (Box 251)
      - Japan (Box 251)
      - Korea (Box 251)
      - Lebanon (Box 251)
      - Libya (Box 251)
      - Pakistan (Box 251)
      - Romania (Box 251)
      - Saudi Arabia (Box 251)
      - Soviet Union (Box 251)
      - Spain (Box 251)
      - Thailand (Box 251)
    - Introduction, Letters of (Box 251)
    - Invitations (Box 251)
    - Journalism: Michigan Journalism Fellows (Box 251)
    - K-12 (Education)
      - General (Box 251)
      - Ann Arbor Schools (Box 251)
      - Detroit Compact (Box 251)
      - Detroit Public Schools (Box 251)
    - Libraries (UM)
      - General (Box 251)
      - Bentley Library (Box 251)
      - Clements Library (Box 251)
      - Ford Library (Box 251)
      - University Library (Box 251)
    - Memberships
      - General, 2 folders (Box 251)
      - Alliance for Undergraduate Education (Box 251)
      - American Academy in Rome (Box 251)
      - American Association for Affirmative Action (Box 251)
      - American Association of University Affiliated Programs (Box 251)
      - American Association of University Women (Box 251)
      - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 251)
      - American Institute of Indian Studies (Box 251)
      - American School of Classical Studies (Athens) (Box 251)
      - American Schools of Oriental Research (Box 251)
      - American Society for Eighteenth Century Studies (Box 251)
      - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce (Box 251)
      - Association for Jewish Studies (Box 251)
      - Association of American Colleges (Box 251)
      - Association of American Health Centers (Box 251)
      - Association of International Education Administrators (Box 251)
      - Association of Michigan Collegiate Faculties (Box 251)
      - Consortium of Social Science Associations (Box 251)
      - Holmes Group (Box 251)
      - International Association of Universities (Box 251)
      - Michigan Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 251)
      - Michigan Energy and Resource Research Association (MERRA) (Box 251)
      - Michigan Health Council (Box 251)
      - Michigan Technology Council (Box 251)
      - Midwest Universities Energy Consortium (Box 251)
      - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (Box 251)
      - Organization for Tropical Studies (Box 251)
      - President's Council of State Colleges and Universities (Box 251)
      - Universities Research Association (Box 251)
    - Michigan, State of
      - General (Box 251)
      - Education, Department of
        - General (Box 251)
        - Michigan Education Trust (MET) (Box 251)
      - Governor's Office (Box 252)
      - Management and Budget, Department of (Box 252)
      - Senators and Representatives (Box 252)
    - Michigan Higher Education Institute (Box 252)
    - Michigan Mandate
      - General, 2 folders (Box 252)
      - Presidential Initiative Fund Proposals, 3 folders (Box 252)
    - Michigan Partnership for New Education (Box 252)
    - Michigan Schools and Colleges
      - General (Box 252)
      - Washtenaw Community College (Box 252)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows (Box 252)
    - Middle East (Box 252)
    - Minority Affairs, Vice Provost for
      - General, 3 folders (Box 252)
      - Admissions and Enrollment (Box 252)
      - African-American (Box 252)
      - Diversity Day (Box 252)
      - Hispanics (Box 252)
      - Jewish Community (Box 252)
      - Native American (Box 252)
    - Multicultural University Council (Box 252)
    - Museums (Box 253)
      - General (Box 253)
      - Art, Museum of (Box 253)
      - Exhibit Museum (Box 253)
      - Kelsey Museum of Archaeology (Box 253)
    - Musical Society, University (UMS) (Box 253)
    - National Organizations
      - General (Box 253)
      - National Academy of Engineering (Box 253)
      - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (Box 253)
      - National Register of Historic Places (Box 253)
      - National Science Board (Box 253)
      - National Science Foundation (NSF)
        - General, 3 folders (Box 253)
        - Complaints (re: tenure) (Box 268)
    - Natural Science (Box 253)
    - North Campus Deans Council (Box 253)
    - Personnel
      - General, 2 folders (Box 253)
      - Complaints and Grievances (Box 268)
      - Faculty, 2 folders (Box 253)
      - Staff Benefits (Box 253)
      - Union Activities (Box 253)
    - Politically Correct (Box 253)
    - Power Foundation (Box 253)
    - Presidential Initiatives Fund (PIF) (Box 253)
    - President's Council of State Universities in Michigan, 3 folders (Box 254)
    - President's Office (Box 254)
    - Professorships, Endowed Chairs, etc.
      - General, 2 folders (Box 254)
      - Recommendations (Box 268)
      - Benton Endowment/Sunderland Fellowship (Box 254)
      - George C. Cameron Professorship in Near Eastern Civilization and Languages (Box 254)
      - James A. and Sarah A. Degan Distinguished Fellowships (Box 254)
      - Helen DeRoy Visiting Professorship (Box 254)
      - Hazel M. Losh Endowed Chair in Astronomy (Box 254)
      - John D. MacArthur Chair in Physics (Box 254)
      - Alex and Marie Manoogian Chair in Modern Armenian Studies (Box 254)
      - Carl Proffer (Box 254)
      - Arthur F. Thurnau Chairs (Box 254)
      - Mary Ann and Charles R. Walgreen, Jr. Professor for the Study of Human Understanding (Box 254)
      - Raoul Wallenberg Chair (Box 254)
      - William Wilhartz Assistant Professorship; Edna and Norman Freehling Gift (Box 254)
      - Isadore and Leon Winkelman Chair in Retail Marketing (Box 254)
    - Provost's Advisory Committee on Excellence (PACE) (Box 254)
    - Public Service (Box 254)
    - Quality Institute (Box 254)
    - Regents
      - General, 3 folders (Box 254)
      - Deane Baker (Box 254)
      - Paul W. Brown (Box 254)
      - Shirley McFee (Box 254)
      - Philip H. Power (Box 254)
      - Thomas A. Roach (Box 254)
      - Veronica Latta Smith (Box 254)
    - Requests (Box 254)
    - Research, Vice President for
      - General, 2 folders
        - folder 1 (Box 254)
        - folder 2 (Box 255)
      - Animal Research (Box 255)
      - Intellectual Properties (Box 255)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) (Box 255)
    - Retreats, Leadership
      - January 8, 1991 (Box 259)
        (2 audiocassettes)
      - September 4, 1990 (Box 259)
      - January 9, 1990 (Box 255)
    - Scholarships (Box 255)
    - Senate, Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), Senate Assembly (Box 255)
    - Smoking (Box 255)
    - State Outreach (Box 255)
    - Statistics (Box 255)
    - Strategic Planning, 4 folders (Box 255)
    - Student Publications (Box 255)
    - Student Services, Vice President for
      - General (Box 255)
      - Consulting Team Visit June, 1991 (Box 255)
      - Greeks (Box 255)
      - Housing (Box 255)
    - Students
      - General (Box 255)
      - Complaint (Box 268)
      - Michigan Student Assembly (MSA) (Box 259)
        (1 audiocassette)
    - Substance Abuse (Box 256)
    - Surveys (Box 256)
    - Tanner Lecture (Box 256)
    - Taubman, A. Alfred (Box 256)
    - Tuition and Fees (Box 256)
    - Undergraduate Education (Box 256)
    - United States
      - General (Box 256)
      - Education, Department of
        - General (Box 256)
        - Office for Civil Rights Complaints (students) (Box 268)
      - Senators and Representatives (Box 256)
    - University Events
      - General (Box 256)
      - Seminar October 1990 (Box 256)
    - University of Michigan
      - General (Box 256)
      - History and Tradition Task Force (Box 256)
    - University Relations
      - General (Box 256)
      - Budget Articles (Box 256)
    - Washtenaw United Way and Development Council (Box 256)
    - Women
      - General (Box 256)
      - President's Advisory Commission (Box 256)
  - 1991-1992
    - Academic Affairs, Vice President for and Provost (Box 262)
      - General (Box 262)
      - Complaints (students) (Box 268)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2067 ]
      - Admissions (Box 262)
      - Financial Aid (Box 262)
    - Accreditation (Box 262)
    - Affirmative Action
      - Office of (Box 262)
      - Gays and Lesbians (Box 262)
      - Sexual Harassment (Box 262)
    - AIDS (Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome) (Box 262)
    - Alumni Association (Box 262)
    - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 262)
    - Ann Arbor (Box 262)
    - Anonymous, etc. (Box 262)
      (miscellaneous correspondence from the public)
    - Articles of Interest (Box 262)
    - Association of American Universities (AAU) (Box 262)
    - Athletics
      - General, 2 folders (Box 262)
      - Big Ten, 2 folders (Box 262)
      - NCAA (Box 262)
      - Rose Bowl 1992 (Box 262)
    - Awards
      - General (Box 262)
      - External (Box 262)
      - Internal
        - General (Box 262)
        - Henry Russel (Box 262)
        - Wallenberg, Raoul (Box 262)
    - Big Ten (Box 262)
    - Budget
      - Indirect Costs, 2 folders (Box 263)
      - University (Box 263)
    - Business Higher Education Forum (Box 263)
    - Business Higher Education Roundtable (Box 263)
    - Campus Compact, Michigan Chapter (Box 263)
    - Campus Issues (Box 263)
    - Campus Safety Task Force (Box 263)
    - Commencement (Box 263)
    - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) (Box 263)
    - Community Affairs, Vice President for (Box 263)
    - Condolences and Get-Well Wishes (Box 263)
    - Conferences and Meetings (Box 263)
    - Congratulations and Commendations (Box 263)
    - Dearborn Campus (Box 263)
    - Detroit (Box 263)
    - Development
      - Vice President for (Box 263)
        (includes b&w photo of President and Mrs. Duderstadt with a plaque of Margaret Towsley at the Schembechler Hall Dedication)
      - Business--Industry (Box 263)
      - Campaign for Michigan, 2 folders (Box 263)
      - Events (Box 263)
      - Foundations
        - General (Box 263)
        - Kellogg Foundation (Box 263)
      - President's Advisory Group (Box 263)
    - Disabled Persons (Box 264)
    - Duderstadt, James J.
      - Notes (Box 264)
      - Personal (Box 264)
      - Speeches, 4 folders (Box 264)
    - Environment (Box 264)
    - Fellowships
      - General (Box 264)
      - Michigan Journalism Fellows (Box 264)
    - Financial Officer, Vice President and Chief (Box 264)
    - Finance
      - Investments and Insurance (Box 264)
      - Parking Operations (Box 264)
      - Plant (Box 264)
      - Public Safety (Box 264)
    - Flint Campus (Box 264)
    - Flint Initiatives (Box 264)
    - General Counsel, Office of
      - General (Box 264)
      - General Counsel Communications (Box 268)
        [CR RESTRICTED July 1, 2092 ]
    - Global Change Project (Box 264)
    - Government Relations
      - Vice President for, 2 folders (Box 264)
      - Events (Box 264)
    - Government-University-Industry Research Roundtable (Box 264)
    - Graduate Student Assistants (GSA) (Box 264)
    - Grievances
      - Faculty/Staff (Box 268)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2022 ]
      - Students (Box 268)
    - Higher Education
      - General, 2 folders (Box 264)
      - Science Education (Box 264)
    - Honorary Degrees, 3 folders (Box 264)
    - Information Technology, Vice Provost for (Box 265)
    - Institutes (UM) (Box 265)
    - Institute for Social Research (ISR) (Box 265)
    - International Issues
      - General, 2 folders (Box 265)
      - International Program Complaint (student) (Box 268)
      - Peace Corps (Box 265)
    - Introduction, Letters of (Box 265)
      (mostly for doctoral students who are doing research outside U-M)
    - K-12
      - General (Box 265)
      - Ann Arbor Schools (Box 265)
      - Detroit Public Schools (Box 265)
    - Libraries
      - General (Box 265)
      - Bentley Historical Library (Box 265)
      - Clements Library (Box 265)
      - University Library (Box 265)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Day (Box 265)
    - Mayer, Sydney (Box 265)
    - Medical Affairs, Vice Provost for
      - General (Box 265)
      - Hospitals (Box 265)
      - M-Care (Box 265)
    - Memberships (Box 265)
    - Michigan, State of
      - General (Box 265)
      - Education, Department of (Box 265)
      - Education Trust (Box 265)
      - Governor's Office (Box 265)
      - Management & Budget, Department of (Box 265)
      - Senators & Representatives (Box 265)
    - Michigan Higher Education Institute (Box 265)
    - Michigan Mandate, Presidential Initiatives Fund (Box 265)
    - Michigan Partnership for New Education (Box 265)
    - Michigan, Schools and Colleges (Box 265)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows (Box 265)
    - Minority Affairs
      - Vice Provost for Minority Affairs (Box 265)
      - African-American (Box 265)
      - Hispanics (Box 265)
      - Jewish Community (Box 265)
        (includes correspondence exchanged with Mark D. Lipton relating to experiences of his father at the University in the 1930s and pertaining to quotas for Jewish students)
      - Native Americans (Box 265)
      - President's Advisory Commission on Minority Affairs (PACMA) (Box 265)
    - Multicultural University Council (Box 265)
    - Musical Society, University (UMS) (Box 265)
    - Museum of Art (UM) (Box 265)
    - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (Box 265)
    - National Academy of Engineering (Box 265)
    - National Science Board and National Science Foundation (Box 265)
    - North Campus, Integrated Technology Instructional Center (Box 265)
    - Personnel
      - General, 2 folders (Box 265)
      - Complaints (faculty/staff) (Box 268)
      - Faculty, 2 folders (Box 265)
      - Staff Benefits (Box 266)
    - Politically Correct, 2 folders (Box 266)
    - Power Foundation, Sarah Goddard Memorial Fund (Box 266)
    - President's Council of State Universities of Michigan, 2 folders (Box 266)
    - President's Office (Box 266)
    - Professorships, Endowed Chairs, etc. (Box 266)
    - Public Service (Box 266)
    - Quality Management, Total (TQM) (Box 266)
    - Regents
      - Baker, Deane (Box 266)
      - Brown, Paul W. (Box 266)
      - McFee, Shirley (Box 266)
      - Nielsen, Neal (Box 266)
      - Power, Philip H. (Box 266)
      - Waters, James A. (Box 266)
    - Research
      - Vice President for (Box 266)
      - Animal Research (Box 266)
      - DRDA (Box 266)
      - Intellectual Properties (Box 266)
    - ROTC (Reserve Officers Training Corps) (Box 266)
    - Scholarships (Box 266)
    - Senate, Senate Advisory (SACUA), Senate Assembly (Box 266)
    - Sigma Xi (Box 266)
    - Smoking (Box 266)
    - Statistics (Box 266)
    - Strategic Planning (Box 266)
    - Student Publications (Box 266)
    - Students
      - General (Box 266)
      - Michigan Student Assembly (MSA) (Box 266)
    - Student Services, Vice President for
      - General (Box 266)
      - Complaints (students) (Box 268)
      - Greeks (Box 266)
      - Housing (Box 266)
    - Substance Abuse (Box 266)
    - Surveys (Box 266)
    - Tanner Lecture (Box 266)
    - Taubman, A. Alfred (Box 266)
    - Tuition and Fees (Box 266)
    - Undergraduate Center Project (Box 266)
    - Undergraduate Education (Box 266)
    - Undergraduate Education Directory (Box 266)
    - United States
      - Education, Department of (Box 266)
      - Senators and Representatives (Box 266)
    - University Events (Box 266)
    - University of Michigan (Box 267)
      - General (Box 267)
      - 175th Anniversary (Box 267)
      - History and Traditions Task Force (Box 267)
    - University Relations, Office of (Box 267)
    - Washtenaw County
      - General (Box 267)
      - United Way (Box 267)
    - Women
      - General (Box 267)
      - President's Advisory Commission on Women (Box 267)
  - 1992-1993
    - Academic Affairs, Vice President and Provost for (Box 269)
      - General, 2 folders (Box 269)
      - Admissions (Box 269)
      - Financial Aid (Box 269)
      - Residency (Box 269)
    - Academic Program Group (APG) (Box 269)
    - Accreditation (Box 269)
    - Affirmative Action
      - Gays and Lesbians (Box 269)
      - Sexual Harassment (Box 269)
    - AIDS (Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome) (Box 269)
    - Alumni Association
      - General (Box 269)
      - Events (Box 269)
    - Ann Arbor (Box 269)
    - Anonymous, etc. (Box 269)
    - Association of American Universities (AAU) (Box 269)
    - Athletics
      - General, 3 folders (Box 269)
      - Big Ten, 2 folders (Box 269)
      - Income Agreements (Box 270)
      - NCAA, 2 folders (Box 270)
      - Rose Bowl (Box 270)
    - Awards
      - Henry Russel (Box 270)
      - University (Box 270)
      - Wallenberg (Box 270)
        (recipient: Helen Suzman)
    - Budget
      - Indirect Costs (Box 270)
      - State (Box 270)
      - University (Box 270)
    - Business Higher Education Forum (Box 270)
    - Business-Industry (Box 270)
    - Campus
      - General (Box 270)
      - Safety (Box 268)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2068 ]
    - Campus Compact (Box 270)
    - Centers (UM) (Box 270)
    - Commencement (Box 270)
      (speaker, information, etc.)
    - Condolences and Get-Well Wishes (Box 270)
    - Conferences and Meetings (Box 270)
    - Congratulations and Commendations (Box 270)
    - Contracts (Box 270)
      (Michigamua and Peace Corps)
    - Dearborn Campus
      - General (Box 270)
      - Chancellor Search (Box 268)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2023 ]
    - Detroit (Box 270)
    - Development, Vice President for
      - General (Box 270)
      - Campaign (Box 270)
        (1 of 2 folders)
      - Campaign (Box 271)
        (2 of 2 folders)
      - Corporations (Box 271)
      - Events (Box 271)
      - Foundations (Box 271)
      - Kellogg Foundation (Box 271)
      - President's Advisory Group (Box 271)
    - Disabled Persons (Box 271)
    - Duderstadt, James J.
      - Notes (Box 271)
      - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 271)
    - Environment (Box 271)
    - Fellowships (Box 271)
    - Financial Officer, Vice President and Chief
      - General (Box 271)
      - Investments and Insurance (Box 271)
      - Parking Operations (Box 271)
      - Plant (Box 271)
      - Plant Extension (Box 271)
    - Flint Campus
      - General (Box 271)
      - Initiatives (Box 271)
    - Free Speech (Box 271)
    - General Counsel, Office of (Box 272)
    - Government-University-Industry Research Roundtable (Box 272)
    - Graduate Student Assistants (Box 272)
    - Grievances (Box 268)
    - Higher Education (Box 272)
    - Honorary Degree (Box 272)
    - Information Technology, Vice Provost for (Box 272)
    - Institutes (UM)
      - General (Box 272)
      - Institute for Social Research (Box 272)
    - Interdisciplinary (Box 272)
    - International
      - Exchange Programs (Box 272)
      - Issues, 2 folders (Box 272)
    - Journalism: Michigan Journalism Fellows (Box 272)
    - K-12
      - Ann Arbor Schools (Box 272)
      - Detroit Public Schools (Box 272)
    - Libraries
      - Bentley Library (Box 272)
      - University Library (Box 272)
    - Mayer, Sidney (Box 272)
    - Michigan (State of)
      - General (Box 272)
      - Education, Department of (Box 272)
      - Governor's Office (Box 272)
      - Management and Budget, Department of (Box 272)
      - Senators and Representatives (Box 272)
    - Michigan College and University Partnership (Box 273)
    - Michigan Joint Manufacturing Initiative (Box 273)
    - Michigan Mandate
      - Initiatives Fund, 3 folders (Box 273)
    - Michigan Society of Fellows (Box 273)
    - Minority Affairs
      - Vice Provost for Minority Affairs (Box 273)